Forrest Shreve photographs, 1902-1940 (bulk 1914-1936)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Forrest Shreve photographs, 1902-1940 (bulk 1914-1936)
AZ 518
This collection consists of 1102 photographs, chiefly of vegetation taken throughout Arizona, New Mexico, California, and Mexico (Sonora and Baja California).
Shreve, Forrest, 1878-1950
1.7 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Other photographs by Forrest Shreve may be located in various folders in the University of Arizona Libraries Special Collections Photograph File.
Biographical Note
Forrest Shreve was a botanist and desert plant ecologist. He served on the staff of the Desert Botanical Laboratory of the Carnegie Institution, Tucson, Arizona, from 1908 to 1929, and as director from 1929 to 1938.
Organization
This collection is organized into two series:
Series I: Photographs, 1902-1940
Series II: Album, 1930-1934
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of 1102 photographs, chiefly of vegetation taken throughout Arizona, New Mexico, California, and Mexico (Sonora and Baja California). It also includes photographs of Shreve and his family, the Desert Botanical Laboratory, early automobile trips, and a number of towns in Sonora, Mexico. Some photographs were taken by Laboratory director, D.T. MacDougal, staff members Godfrey Sykes and H.S. Gentry, and others.
Access Terms
Desert Botanical Laboratory of the Carnegie Institution -- Photographs
Botany -- Sonoran Desert -- Photographs
Botany -- Mexico -- Baja California (Peninsula) -- Photographs
Botany -- Mexico -- Sonora (State) -- Photographs
Desert plants -- Arizona -- Photographs
Desert plants -- Mexico -- Baja California (Peninsula) -- Photographs
Desert plants -- Sonoran Desert -- Photographs
Mojave Desert (Calif.) -- Photographs
Sonoran Desert -- Photographs
Sonora (Mexico: State) -- Description and travel -- Photographs
Arizona -- Description and travel -- Photographs
Salton Sea (Calif.) -- Photographs
Photographs
Related Material
For related material see AZ 566, AZ 356, and AZ 425
Separated Material
The following photographs received with this collection were removed at cataloged separately:
View of Tucson from the Blake house near the University of Arizona campus, 1907
Tucson street scene, 1908
Picture Rocks, near Tucson, photos by Edith Clements (6 photographs), 1913
Ostrich Farm, possibly on the University of Arizona campus (2 photographs), 1914
Tucson street scene, 1915
Congress Street Bridge, Tucson, across the Santa Cruz River, 1915
University of Arizona cactus garden (2 photographs), 1915
Views of Tucson from Tumamoc Hill (2 photographs), 1916
Tucson street scenes (2 photographs), 1916
Train wreck near Maricopa, Arizona, 1924
Ajo, Arizona, 1929
Columbus, New Mexico and Pershing's troops (6 photographs), April 1916
San Atonio de Padua Mission, Jolan, California (3 photographs), no date
Container List
- Series I: Photographs, 1902-1940
  - Personal and Arizona Photographs, 1904-1933
    - Forrest Shreve (14 photographs). (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Family and homes (20 photographs). (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - River crossings at flood time (9 photographs). 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Carnegie Desert Botanical Laboratory buildings, staff, surroundings (36 photographs). 1914-1915, 1924, 1930s (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Catalina Mountains (26 photographs). 1904-1914 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Notebook: Arizona. 1913 (Box 1)
      Havalina Canon and Tortolita Mountains (5 photographs)
      Chaparral near Prescott
      Grand Canyon
      San Francisco Peaks and forests (17 photographs)
    - Notebook: Arizona I. 1914 (Box 1)
      Silver Bell Pass, Tucson Mountains (3 photographs)
      Havalina Canon, Tortolita Mountains (3 photographs)
      Rosemont and Empire Ranch (11 photographs)
      Pima Canon, Catalina Mountains (7 photographs)
      Black Mountain, Tortolita Mountains and Suffering Camp (18 photographs)
      Mount Fagan, Santa Rita Mountains (28 photographs)
      Catalina Mountains (12 photographs)
      Ventana Canon, Catalina Mountains (8 photographs)
      Trip: San Pedro River, Dragoon and Mountains, Willcox, Dos Cabesas, Artesia, Safford (40 photographs)
      Trip: Pearce, Tombstone, Empire Ranch, Davidson's Canon (48 photographs)
      Vegetation west of Gleeson; also near Tombstone (2 photographs)
    - Notebook: Arizona II. 1914 (Box 1)
      Graham Mountains, Frye Canon (38 photographs)
      Desert scenes (2 photographs)
      Catalina Mountains from Speedway, December 1914 (2 photographs)
      Catalina Mountains (7 photographs)
    - Notebook: Arizona I. 1915 (Box 2)
      Tumamoc Hill; Catalina Mountains; Tucson Mountains (12 photographs)
      Davidson's Canon; Empire Mountains (10 photographs)
      Giant cactus and desert scenes (10 photographs)
      Catalina Mountains (4 photographs)
      San Pedro River (7 photographs)
      Colorado River at Parker
      Vegetation near Midway, Yuma County
      Unidentified (8 photographs)
    - Notebook: Arizona II. 1915 (Box 2)
      Trip: Coyote Mountains, Comabai, Poso Blanco, Tonoka, Ajo, desert scenes, Casa Grande, Papago groups, Tucson Mountains (63 photographs)
    - Notebook: Arizona. 1916 (Box 2)
      Greaterville (5 photographs)
      Trip: Desert Well, Wickenburg, Camp Verde, Montezuma's Well, northern Arizona, Grand Canyon (36 photographs)
      San Pedro Valley, Huachuca Mountains, desert scenes (15 photographs)
    - Arizona Photographs. 1926-1933 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Catalina Mountains, 1923, (4 photographs)
      Baboquivari Mountains, 1923, (5 photographs)
      Automobiles, near Flagstaff, 1923
      Roosevelt Lake and area, 1925, (10 photographs)
      Boyce Thompson Arboretum and Picket Post, 1925, (3 photographs)
      Craig Ranch, Pinal Mountains, 1925
      Giant cactus, 1925, (6 photographs)
      Near Yucca, Arizona, 1929
      Near Sabino Canon, 1930
      "The Office," 1930
      Huachuca Mountains, 1932, (2 photographs)
      Tule Tank; Cabeza Prieta, etc., 1932, (3 photographs)
      Chiricahua Mountains, 1933, (2 photographs)
      Cabeza Prieta Mountains, 1933, (2 photographs)
  - New Mexico, California and Mexico Photographs, 1902-1936
    - Notebook: New Mexico. 1911, 1929 (Box 3)
      Ortero Basin, 1911, (9 photographs)
      Sacramento Mountains, 1911, (11 photographs)
      Cloudcroft, 1911, (2 photographs)
      Tularosa Creed and Canon, 1911 (3 photographs)
      Mescalero Indian Reservation and Agency, 1911, (3 photographs)
      Elephant Butte Dam, 1929
      Vegetation along Rio Grande River below Socorro, 1929 (2 photographs)
      La Lunas home, 1929
      Jemez Canon, 1929, (2 photographs)
      Unidentified (2 photographs)
    - Notebook: California. 1902, 1914-1916, 1924, 1936 (Box 3)
      Eucalyptus tree, 1902
      Mohave Desert, 1914-1915, (38 photographs)
      Pine Valley, Cuyauaca Mountains, 1916, (4 photographs)
      Carrizo Gorge, 1924, (2 photographs)
      Salton Sea and Basin, 1924, (8 photographs)
      Trip from Tucson to San Diego, sand dunes, 1936, (8 photographs)
    - Sonora, Mexico Photographs. 1923, 1925-1926 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      Sasabe, Altar, Pitiquito, 1923 (26 photographs)
      Altar, Poza Verrugo, 1925, (33 photographs)
      Libertad, 1926, (5 photographs)
    - Sonora, Mexico Photographs. 1930-1933, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Pozo Serna, Libertad, Los Molinos, Santo Domingo, 1930, (22 photographs)
      Mission San Pedro de Tubutama and Mission San Antonio de Aquitoa, 1931 (4 photographs)
      Imuris, Magdela, Santa Ana, Horcasitas, Mission San Ignacio de Caborica, the tanks in the Sierra Picu, 1932, (31 photographs)
      La Misa, Punta Piedras, Cedros, Port Lobos, 1933, (14 photographs)
      Culiacan, 1936, (13 photographs)
      Yaqui River, no dates (2 photographs)
    - Sinaloa, Mexico Photographs by H. S. Gentry (12 photographs). 1939-1940 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Baja California, Mexico (23 photographs). 1915, 1922, 1924 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Non-Southwestern and Unidentified Photographs
    - Non-Southwestern Photographs by various artists. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      Florida
      New South Wales (9 photographs)
      New York
      New Zealand
      Oregon (2 photographs)
      Pennsylvania
      Washington
      Unidentified (14 photographs)
    - Unidentified Photographs (7 photographs). (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Series II: Album, 1930-1934
  - Arizona Photographs (26 photographs).
    Tucson Mountains
    Tortolita Mountains
    Santa Cruz floodplain
    Papago Bell, Tule Tank
    Camino del Diablo
    San Rafael Valley
    Mohave County
  - Sonora, Mexico Photographs (107 photographs).
    Batuc
    Ures
    Moctezuma
  - Baja California, Mexico Photographs (97 photographs).
    Calmalli
    San Marcos Island
    Mission of San Ignacio de Kadakahamang
  - Mohave Desert, California Photographs (3 photographs).